I'm a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I went to the amusement park
和青梅竹马的毛利兰
with my childhood friend Ran Mouri,
一起去游乐场玩的时候
I witnessed a suspicious transaction of a man in black.
目击了黑衣男子进行可疑交易的现场
As I was focused on the ongoing transaction,
专注于偷看交易进行的我
I didn't notice the other man in black, who was the accomplice, behind my back,
没有察觉到从身后接近的另一名黑衣人同伙
and I was poisoned by that man.
我被那个男人灌下毒药
When I woke up...
当我醒来时...
my body shrank.
身体竟然缩小了
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
如果让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着
it'll endanger the safety of my relatives and friends.
还会危及到身边亲友的安全
Following the advice of Professor Agasa, I hid my true identity.
在阿笠博士的建议下我隐藏了真实身份
When Ran asked for my name,
在小兰问我名字的时候
I came up with Conan Edogawa at an instant.
灵机一动回答说自己叫江户川柯南
To get more information about those men in black,
为了得到那些黑衣人的情报
I stayed at Ran's house, whose father is a detective.
就寄住在了父亲是侦探的小兰家
I'm a high school detective in Osaka, Heiji Hattori.
我是大阪的高中生侦探服部平次
I inherited my detective and Kendo skills
推理和剑道的能力
from my father, who was the head of the Osaka Prefecture Police Department,
是从做大阪府警本部长的爸爸那儿遗传来的
and I inherited self-possession from my mother.
而冷静沉着则是妈妈的遗传
By the way, I got my dark skin from grandpa.
顺便说一下  皮肤黑是爷爷的遗传
We were once known as the Kudo of Kanto, and Hattori of Kansai.
我们以前被并称为关东的工藤  关西的服部
Though I'm on par with Kudo,
我虽和工藤不相上下
Kudo is truly quite something.
但真不愧是工藤啊
He used the unique tools invented by Professor Agasa
他运用阿笠博士发明的奇特工具
and solved many cases one after another.
接连不断的解决了很多案件
Other than the Professor and myself,
知道工藤真实身份的人
those who know about the true identity of Kudo,
除了我和博士之外
include the parents of Kudo
还有工藤的爸爸  妈妈
as well as Ai Haibara, the girl who goes to the same elementary school as Kudo.
以及和工藤上同一所小学的灰原哀
This little girl used to be a member of the Black Organization
这个小丫头曾经是黑衣组织的成员
While fleeing the organization,
在逃离组织的时候
she took the same poison as Kudo
吃下了和工藤一样的毒药
and her body also shrank.
身体也缩小了
Speaking of that, I also have a childhood friend who's also my classmate,
说起来我也有个青梅竹马又是同班同学
Kazuha Toyama.
叫远山和叶的
A very long-winded woman.
很啰嗦的女人
Who's this long-winded person?
你说谁很啰嗦
Hey, don't just jump out of nowhere, idiot.
喂  不要突然跳出来啊  白痴
You're an idiot. Who are you talking to?
你才是白痴呢  在对着谁说话啊
What do you mean who?
什么谁啊
I'm explaining to the audience in simple language,
我在用通俗易懂的语言给各位观众解释呢
right?
对吧
Do you have a problem?
你不会是脑袋有毛病了吧
You're the one with a problem.
有毛病的是你吧
Even though I've shrunk down, my brain still works as it should.
就算变小了头脑依然灵活
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
We've arrived at Beika Station, the exit...
(米花站到了 出口在...)
So that means you still can't come back yet?
这么说你还是不能回来吗
Yeah, I'm busy investigating the case.
是啊  忙着调查案子
I see.
这样啊
It's quite cold these days. Stay warm.
最近天气一直很冷  要当心身体啊
Don't sleep with your belly exposed.
你也不要露着肚皮睡觉哟
I don't have my belly exposed, idiot.
我哪有露着肚皮啊  笨蛋
The snow on Mount Yoshino, my longings,
吉野山的白雪啊  我的思念
The one who left me, when will I see you again?
离开我的人儿啊  何日再见
You guys are not Yoshitsune and Shizuka Gozen.
你们又不是义经和静御前
What?
什么啊
I'm worried if there's anything wrong with my childhood friend.
我担心我的青梅竹马又有什么不对
Dad is being long-winded. I'm hanging up.
爸爸好啰嗦  我挂了
Hello? Hello?
喂  真是的
I should call next time when Uncle is not around.
下次等叔叔不在的时候再打好了
Yoshitsune and Shizuka Gozen,
义经和静御前
didn't these two stop seeing each other after they separated?
那两人不是分开之后就没能再见过面吗
Hey...hey.
喂喂
(Tokyo  Kunitachi City)
[东京.西国立市]
(Kamei Rokuro, 35)
[龟井六郎(35)]
(Kataoka Hachiro, 34)
[片冈八郎(34)]
(Shichiro Washio, 35)
[鹫尾七郎(35)]
Benkei is so slow.
弁庆这家伙真慢啊
He said he solved the riddle already.
他说已经把谜题解开了
This is what the guy's interested in the most.
那家伙对这个最感兴趣了
Kataoka.
片冈
(Osaka  Late Night)
[大阪(深夜)]
(Neyagawa "Takodaira")
[寝屋川市『章鱼平』]
(Heishiro Bizen, 35)
[备前平四郎(35)]
(Kyoto  Early morning)
[京都(凌晨)]
(Higashiyama "Jiro Bar")
[东山区『次郎酒吧』]
(Jiro Suruga, 32)
[骏河次郎(32)]
(A Few Days Later Tokyo. Metropolitan Police Department)
[数日后  东京.警视厅]
According to the results of the investigation,
根据调查的结果得知
the 5 victims killed in Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto
在东京  大阪  京都被杀害的5个人
were all members of Genjibotaru, the gang of robbers.
都是强盗团伙源氏萤的成员
Therefore, this case...
因此  这次的案件...
(Kyoto Prefecture Police Department Inspector, Fumimaro Ayanokoji) Sato,
[京都府警警部  绫小路文鹰]
I heard that Inspector Fumimaro Ayanokouji from the Kyoto Prefecture Police Department
听说那个京都府警绫小路警部 [京都府警警部  绫小路文鹰]
joined the police force at the same time as the Shiratori.
和白鸟警部是同时进入警界的
Yes, I heard that he's from a royal family and everyone calls him the “Royal Inspector".
是啊  听说是官宦子弟  外号“贵族警部”
Look at his left pocket.
看他左边的口袋
Wh-What's that?
那...那是什么
His pet chipmunk.
是他的宠物斑纹松鼠
I heard that he carries it everywhere.
听说一直带在身边的哦
He's weirder than Shiratori, right?
是个比白鸟还要怪的人吧
Genjibotaru, since the third year of Heisei (1991),
源氏萤从平成三年(1991年)起
have been active mostly in Tokyo, Kyoto and Osaka
以东京  京都和大阪为中心
and mainly been stealing Buddhist statues and artworks.
主要偷盗有名的佛像和美术品
They have a special feature,
他们的特征是
as their members would call each other by the names of Yoshitsune's subordinates,
所有成员都以义经的家臣名字互相称呼
and every member possesses a copy of "Chronicles of Yoshitsune"
都持有一本《义经记》
("Chronicles of Yoshitsune") They all have a copy of "Chronicles of Yoshitsune"
[《义经记》]
The leader is Yoshitsune.
首领是义经
The following eight people includes Benkei and Iseno Saburo.
以下是弁庆  伊势三郎等共八个人
This time, except for these three, the other five have all been killed.
本次除这三人外的其余五人都被杀害
Their Yoshitsune books have also been taken away.
他们所持的《义经记》也都被人拿走了
How about clues on the murderer?
关于凶手的线索呢
(Osaka Prefectural Officer Otaki) I can be certain that he's a master of Kendo and archery
可以肯定是个剑道和弓箭的高手
(Osaka Prefecture Officer Otaki) As for Yoshitsune, Benkei and Iseno Saburo,
至于义经  弁庆和伊势三郎三人
we don't know their ages or genders yet.
他们的年龄和性别都还不清楚
No matter what,
不管怎么样
we need to bring the murderer
要尽快将
and other members of the gang to justice as soon as possible.
凶手和盗贼团伙其他的成员绳之以法
The search will continue.
搜查仍将继续进行
Yoshitsune from the Heisei era
平成年代的义经
turned out to be a leader of a gang of robbers.
竟是盗贼团伙的头目
Hattori, are you there?
平次你在吗
Come on, isn't this a very important thing?
真是的  这不是很重要的东西嘛
Yes, indeed, it's got to be stored well.
是  是啊  一定要收藏好才行
Hattori, are you going out?
平次你要出去吗
Yes, I've got something I want to investigate.
是啊  有些事情想调查一下
Is there a problem?
有什么事吗
I wanted to go see the cherry blossoms with you at the Ryokuchi Park.
本来想找你一同去友吕岐绿地看樱花的
But it's okay.
不过没关系啦
Really? Then I'll be heading out.
是吗  那么我先走了
Be careful.
小心点啊
Okay.
嗯
Why do I have to put on a smile and send him out of the door?
我干嘛一定要摆个笑脸送他出去啊
Kyoto is truly the hometown for us Japanese.
京都到底是我们日本人的故乡啊
Listen up, I invited you guys to come along out of good will,
听好了  这次是特别优待你们来的
don't interfere with my work.
不能妨碍我工作哦
Roger that.
遵命
So jealous that Conan gets to go to Kyoto.
真羡慕柯南可以去京都啊
It seems that Mouri received a call from a temple called Sannou Temple.
好像是毛利接到了一个叫山能寺的寺庙的委托
We want to go to Kyoto as well.
我们也想去京都啊
I can take you guys there.
我倒是也可以带你们去啦
Really?
是真的吗
Then I'll get to see Conan.
这样就能见到柯南了
Kyoto, Kyoto, let's go to Kyoto tomorrow.
京都京都  明天就去京都
-Kyoto, Kyoto, let's go to Kyoto tomorrow. -But you have to solve the riddle before you can go.
不过你们得先解开谜题才可以去哦
Here we go again.
又来了
You don't really want to take us there, do you?
反正你也不是真想带我们去对吧
What does it matter?
这有什么关系
Tell us about it.
说说看吧
We can pass the time.
正好可以打发时间
What do we do?
怎么办
Let's give it a try.
试试看吧
That's true.
说得也是
The three of you know who Benkei is, right?
你们三个都知道弁庆是谁吧
He's Yoshitsune's subordinate, right?
是义经的家将对吧
Who is Yoshitsune?
义经是谁啊
Nicknamed Ushiwakamaru,
乳名叫牛若丸
he defeated Benki,
在京都的五条大桥上
who wanted to take his 1000th sword, on the Gojou Bridge in Kyoto.
打败了想来抢夺第一千把刀的弁庆
He took Benki in as his subordinate and he renamed himself as Youshitsune.
收他为家将后自己改名为源义经
Genji and Heiki were fighting at the time,
当时源氏和平氏正在打仗
and although Yoshitsune defeated Heiki,
义经虽然打败了平氏
he was despised by his brother, Yoritomo.
却遭到兄长源赖朝的厌恶
Finally, in what we know as Iwate Prefecture today,
最后在现今的岩手县
Yoshitsune committed suicide.
平泉伊川自杀了
You know it so well.
知道得还真清楚呢
There is your question here,
这里就有个问题了
Benki had a first love, named Uzune.
弁庆有一个叫涡奈的初恋情人
But this girl was going to marry another man,
但这个女孩要和别的男人结婚了
and after Benki got the news, he
弁庆知道了以后
1. got angry.
1  发怒了
2. was happy
2  高兴
3. cried.
3  哭了
So which is the right answer?
那么  答案是哪一个呢
Well, it's a first love,
初恋情人啊
of course he got angry,
当然是发怒了啊
How could he be happy?
怎么可能高兴呢
So you choose the first answer. That he got angry.
那么答案就是第一个发怒了哦
Cried.
哭了
The answer is that he cried.
答案是第三个哭了
You came up with this from "Benkei's sore spot", right?
是从“弁庆的痛处”想出来的吧
I really can't win over Ai.
真是赢不了小哀啊
What is "Benkei's sore spot"?
什么是“弁庆的痛处”啊
In other words, even for someone who is as strong as Benki,
就是说即使是像弁庆那样厉害的人
there'll be a weak spot that would make him cry if he gets hit at that spot.
也会有一个被踢到就会痛得流泪的弱点
It's here. The mukouzune (the spot below the knee), that's "Benkei's sore spot."
就是这里  胫骨(小腿前侧)就是“弁庆的痛处”
But does this have anything to do with the riddle?
可是这和谜题有什么关系吗
Well…
啊  这个嘛
I got it!
我懂了
The couple getting married are Mukou and Uzune.
要结婚的是新郎和涡奈
(When combined, it's mukouzune, the spot below the knee.) When Mukou marries Uzune, you get "mukouzune".
新郎(muko)和涡奈(uzune)连起来就是胫骨(mukouzune)
Another lame joke.
又是冷笑话
But the answer's correct.
可是都答对了啊
We can go to Kyoto now.
我们可以去京都了
But Ai was the one who answered it correctly.
可是答对的是小哀啊
Haibara is also a member of us Detective Boys.
灰原也是我们少年侦探团的一员啊
Please don't exclude Huihara from us.
请不要把灰原排除在我们之外
Mom said that an adult who goes back on his words is the worst.
妈妈说不守信用的大人是最差劲的
Thank you for visiting.
多谢惠顾
No need.
不谢不谢
(Sannou Temple)
[山能寺]
Don't tell others what I told you guys last time.
上次和你们说的那件事不能说出去哟
(Ryuen 34, Monk of Sannou Temple)
[龙圆(34)  山能寺的和尚]
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
Welcome.
欢迎您远道而来
I'm Ryuen, the person who called you.
我就是给您打电话联络的龙圆
Let me make the introductions.
给您介绍一下
(Enkai, 65, the Chief priest of Sannou Temple) This is the Chief priest, Enkai.
[圆海(65)  山能寺的住持]
The three here are the benefactors of this temple.
这边的三位是本寺的施主
(Shozo Sakura, 51, antique art dealer) This is Mr. Shozo Sakura.
[樱正造(51)  古董美术品商人]
He runs an antique shop on Teramachi Street.
在寺町大街经营古董店 [樱正造(51)  古董美术品商人]
Are you the famous Kogoro Mouri?
你就是那个有名的毛利小五郎吗
Really? Am I that famous?
哪里  我这么有名吗
(Mizuo Harutaro, 33, Noh actor) This is the young heir to the Noh performance,
[水尾春太郎(33)  能剧演员]
Mr. Shuntaro Mizuo.
水尾春太郎先生 [水尾春太郎(33)  能剧演员]
(Taiga Saijo, 35, old bookstore owner) Then there is Mr. Taiga Saijo, who owns an ancient bookstore.
然后是开古书店的西条大河先生
Nice to meet you.
请多关照
Everyone practices kendo?
大家都练剑道啊
No wonder the Chief Priest looks very energetic.
怪不得住持看上去也精神矍铄呢
Kendo friends?
剑道同好啊
I heard that there is a secret treasure in the temple that is only exhibited to the public once every twelve years.
听说寺里有件十二年才展出一次的密宝
Yes, it is the Healing Buddha statue.
是的  就是药师如来的佛像
The next occasion is just three days away, right?
大后天就是开放参观的日子了吧
We also wanted to see it, so we came here specially for it.
我们也很想看所以才特地过来的
In this case, the Healing Buddha will be very happy as well.
这样的话药师如来也会很高兴的哦
What? The Buddha statue was stolen?
什么  主佛像被偷了
Yes, that was already eight years ago.
是的  那已经是八年前的事了
(Sunlight Bodhisattva) The one on the right is Sunlight Bodhisattva.
[日光菩萨]
(Moonlight Bodhisattva) The one on the left is Moonlight Bodhisattva.
[月光菩萨]
But the Buddha statue in the middle is gone.
可是正中间的如来佛像不见了
I wanted to call the police right away,
我本想马上去报警
but was stopped by the Chief Priest.
但是被住持阻止了
He said it might come back if it was meant to be.
他说如果有缘的话说不定会回来的
You're very optimistic about this.
怎么这么想得开啊
Then eight years has passed.
然后八年过去了
Just five days ago,
就在五天前
I found this letter in the mailbox of the temple.
在寺里的信筒里发现了这封信
There's no stamp nor name of the sender.
没贴邮票  也没写寄件人的姓名
Solve this riddle and you will find the whereabouts of the Buddha statue.
只要解开这幅画的谜就能知道佛像所在了
What kind of painting is this?
这是什么画啊
Thanks, uncle.
谢了  大叔
Sure enough, there were no witnesses to the case that happened in the early hours of the morning.
果然凌晨发生的案件没有目击者啊
Robber!
强盗啊
Get out of my way!
滚开
Ouch! You're going to pay for this!
好痛  你给我记住
Got hit on the mukouzune, it hurts.
打到了弁庆的痛处  很痛的哦
Here you go. Is this yours, Madam?
给  是这个吧  大婶
Thank you. You were awesome just now.
谢谢  小兄弟刚才很帅啊
Don't mention it. It's alright.
哪里哪里  还好了
(Tae Yamakura, 52, Miyagawa teahouse owner) My family owns a teahouse in Miyagawa.
我家是在宫川町开茶屋的
My name is Tae Yamakura.
我叫山仓多惠
Come on, introduce yourself, too.
来啊  你也介绍一下嘛
(Suzu Chika, 19, Geisha) Okay.
[千贺铃(19)  舞妓]
My name is Suzu Chika, nice to meet you.
我叫千贺铃  请多多关照 [千贺铃(19)  舞妓]
How can I thank you?
该怎么答谢你呢
No need, it's not a big deal.
不用了  又不是什么了不起的事
Come hang out at the store next time.
下次一定记得来店里玩
Be safe on the way back.
回去小心一点
Thanks.
谢谢
What does this painting mean?
这幅画到底是什么意思呢
On the fifth row on top,
在最上面的第五层上画的是
there's a cicada, a tengu, and a goldfish.
蝉  天狗和金鱼
On the fourth row, there's a chicken and a loach.
往下的第四层上是公鸡和泥鳅
The yellow loach is really disgusting.
黄色的泥鳅真是恶心
What is this dot?
这一点又是什么呢
Is it dirt?
不过是弄脏了吧
In the middle of the second and third row,
在第二层和第三层的中间
there's a violet, tengu, and Mount Fuji.
是紫罗兰  天狗和富士山
There's also an acorn next to it.
旁边还有个橡栗哦
Dad, can you find it before the day after tomorrow?
爸爸  能在大后天之前找到吗
Don't worry.
不用担心
This kind of painting doesn't even constitute a riddle for me.
这种画对我来说根本连谜题都算不上
Hey, seriously?
喂喂  真的假的啊
I'll leave it to the experts to find the Buddha statue.
找佛像的事就交给专家
Let's go and visit Kyoto.
我们去参观京都吧
That's it.
就这样就这样
You will only disturb me here.
你们在这里只会打扰我而已
Actually, I've already gotten in touch with Toyama,
其实我已经和和叶联系好了
and I asked her to be our Kyoto tour guide tomorrow.
让她明天给我们当导游去京都玩
But Hattori seems to have something going on and he can't come.
可是服部好像有事不能来
It doesn't matter if the boys who already have girlfriends come or not.
已经有女朋友的男生来不来都无所谓啦
That guy is not coming?
那家伙不来啊
Conan, let's go together.
柯南也一起去吧
I won't be going.
我就不去了
I have a date with a kid nearby to go fishing by the river.
我和附近的小孩约好去河边钓鱼的
You've made friends so soon.
这么快就交到朋友了啊
Be careful.
要小心哦
First of all, it seems that the Buddha statue was stolen from Sannou Temple.
首先看来从山能寺偷走佛像的
It must be Genjibotaru.
肯定是源氏萤
But who on earth sent this painting, and for what purpose?
但是到底是谁为了什么目的寄来这幅画呢
And what does it have to do with the five murder cases?
而且和那五宗凶杀案又有什么关系呢
Genjibotaru...
源氏萤...
Talking about Yoshitsune and Benkei,
如果说到义经和弁庆的话
it should still be there.
应该还是那里
(Gojou Bridge)
[五条大桥]
Nothing seems to be related to the riddle in the painting.
好像没什么和画里的谜题有关系的东西
On the Gojou Bridge in Kyoto,
在京都的五条大桥上
the strongman Benkei wields a long sword
壮士弁庆挥动长刀
and initiates an attack toward Ushiwakamaru.
朝牛若丸砍去
Hattori…
服  服部
I can't believe that I'd meet you here.
和你在这里碰到真是老天爷捉弄人呀
Hey, give me the bamboo knife.
大哥哥  把竹刀还给我啊
Sorry. Thank you.
不好意思  谢谢啊
Hey, let's go.
喂  我们走吧
Work hard on your practice.
要好好练习哦
Why did you borrow a bamboo knife?
你这家伙借竹刀干嘛啊
What are you doing in this kind of place?
你在这种地方做什么
And what are you doing here?
那你又是在做什么呢
Actually I know the owner of the Takoyaki shop who was killed in Osaka.
其实我认识在大阪被杀的章鱼丸店老板
Although he was a member of a robber's gang,
虽然是盗贼团伙的成员
I used to go to that store since I was in junior high school
不过从初中的时候我就经常去那家店
and he took good care of me, so
还受到过不少照顾  所以
I wanted to find the murderer for him.
我想找出凶手替他报仇
That's why you came to Kyoto looking for clues.
所以你才来京都寻找线索
In this case, I have something to show you.
这样的话我倒是有好东西给你看哦
I see.
原来如此
If you solve the riddle in this painting,
只要解开这幅画的谜题
you might not only find the Buddha statue,
不仅能找到佛像
but also the murderer.
说不定还能找出凶手
So you...
这么说你也...
Yes, if it is Genjibotaru who stole the Buddha statue,
是啊  如果偷佛像的是源氏萤的话
then we might find clues to solving the riddle
那么在跟义经和弁庆有关的地方
in places related to Yoshitsune and Benkei.
说不定就可以找到解开谜题的线索
But I am not familiar with Kyoto at all.
可是我对京都一点都不熟悉
Then leave it to me.
那接下来就交给我吧
I will show you the way.
我给你带路
(Gojyoten Shrine)
[五条天神]
This is Gojyoten Shrine.
这里就是五条天神
"Chronicles of Yoshitsune" records that the two weren't on the Gojyouoohashi bridge,
《义经记》上说两人并不是在五条大桥
instead, they met here for the first time.
而是在这里初次相识
How is it? Is there anything in common?
怎么样  有什么共通点吗
Doesn't look like it.
看上去好像没有什么
Then let's head to the next place,
那么我们就去下一个地方
That's really upsetting.
可是真是不爽
Why didn't the monks at Sannou Temple come to me?
为什么山能寺的和尚不来找我呢
When it comes to detectives in Kansai, it should be me, right?
在关西说到侦探的话应该是我吧
Maybe they didn't want the police to know,
他们可能是不想让警察知道吧
since your dad is a senior police officer.
因为你爸是警界高官嘛
Forget it.
算了
Wait, in that case…
等等  这么说起来...
Here it is. Right here.
到了  就这里
(Benkei Stone) Benkei Stone.
[弁庆石]
Some says that's the stone that Benkai often sat on,
有的说是弁庆经常坐的石头
while others say it is a stone thrown down from Mount Hie.
有的说是比叡山上扔下来的石头
In short, there are many legends.
总之有很多种传说
That doesn't seem to have anything to do with this either.
好像和这里也没有什么关系
Really?
是吗
Let's check out the next one then.
那就下一个
Where's the next one?
下一个在哪里
Keage Slope.
蹴上斜坡
I'm a Kyoto Prefecture police officer, Ayanokoji.
我是京都府警  绫小路
I know you are investigating Genjibotaru's case,
我知道你在调查源氏萤的案件
but this is not Osaka.
但是这里不是大阪
It's best for the laymen not to be nosy.
外行最好不要多管闲事
It's a chipmunk.
是松鼠啊
Watch out for yourself.
好自为之
There are strange police officers like this everywhere.
哪里都有这种奇怪的警官啊
(Kiyomizudera Temple)
[清水寺]
Let's take some pictures.
我们来拍照吧
Make sure you get the cherry blossoms, too.
要把樱花也拍到哟
So beautiful.
真美啊
If I get to see such a beautiful view with Kyogoku,
这么美丽的景色
it'll be such a blessing.
能和阿真一起看的话一定幸福死了
Ran, seriously.
小兰  你真是的
It's my turn this time.
这次轮到我说你了
Toyama, did you have a fight with Hattori?
和叶  你是不是和服部吵架了
Actually Heiji also came to Kyoto to investigate a case,
其实平次为了调查某个案子也来京都了
and Heiji's first love is also in Kyoto.
而且平次他的初恋情人也在京都
(Keage Slope Canal Park)
[蹴上斜坡疏水公园]
(Perfected Great Sun Buddha)
[义经大日如来]
This doesn't seem to be right either.
这里好像也不对啊
Let's go and grab lunch.
我们去吃午饭吧
OK.
好啊
Cherry blossoms.
樱花啊
I always recall what happened 8 years ago
只要看到樱花我总是会想起
when I see cherry blossoms.
八年前的事
At that time, I went on an adventure in temples in Kyoto,
那时我到京都的寺庙探险
and I accidentally hit the lattice window of the temple.
不小心撞到了寺庙的格子窗
Even the wooden frame was broken.
连木格都被撞断了
I hit my head hard on the floor
头撞到了地板上
and passed out.
就这么晕了过去
I was out for an unknown period of time.
不知道昏睡了多久
When I woke up…
等我醒过来的时候
After Shichijo comes Hachi-Kujo
过了八条街就是东寺道
Kujo, toji comes at the end.
穿过九条大街就到了
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹  夷二  押御池
Ane-San-Rokkaku-Tako-Nishiki
新娘  六角  蛸锦
Shi-Aya-Butsu-Taka-Matsu-Man-Gojo
四绫佛  高松  万五条
Setta-Chara, chara-Uonotana.
雪靴  叮叮当当  鱼架
It felt like a dream.
虽然好像做梦一样
But it was real.
但却是真实的
I always think we'll meet again.
总觉得什么时候一定可以再和她邂逅
What are you laughing about?
你在笑什么
Sorry, please continue.
对不起对不起  你继续
I always bring this with me when I come to Kyoto.
我到京都来总会把这个带在身边
Crystal bead.
水晶珠
I seem to have seen it somewhere.
好像在哪里看到过
Really?
真的吗
There's someone with the same crystal?
谁也有和这一样的珠子吗
No.
没有
So does she know about it?
那么  她知道这件事吗
She?
她
You mean Toyama?
你是说和叶啊
Although I never told her the details,
虽然我没有和她详细说过
she seems to know.
但她好像是知道的
She knew it because...
她知道这件事是因为...
The interview in the magazine.
杂志的采访报道
Yes, it is the most popular magazine in Kansai.
对  是关西最受欢迎的杂志
Heiji was asked who his first love was,
当时平次被问到初恋情人是谁
and he said she's someone he met in third grade of elementary school
他回答说是小学三年级的时候
who's slightly older than him.
遇到的比他稍大一点的女孩子
He also said he got a precious token from the girl,
还说从女孩那儿拿到了珍贵的信物
and went out of his way to pose for this photo.
还特地拍了这种照片
What is this?
这是什么啊
Just a crystal bead.
只是个水晶珠子而已
Maybe that girl dropped it.
大概是那个女孩子掉的吧
So you know that girl?
那你认识那个女孩子喽
How would I?
我怎么可能认识呢
Heiji only met her once,
平次也只见过她一次
so every time I come to Kyoto, I will ask about her.
所以每次来京都会打听她
That's why he took the photos with the crystal bead.
所以才把水晶珠也拍进了照片
He probably wanted that girl
他大概是想让那个女孩子
to get in touch with him after reading the interview.
看到这篇报道后来和他联系
Right, what a damn thing.
对吧  真是可恶的家伙
He even posted a photo of himself as a kid.
而且连自己小时候的照片都登上去了
So cute.
真可爱
Right? Right? Heiji was super cute back then...
对吧对吧  那时候的平次超级可爱...
Ran, this is not the point,
小兰  这不是重点啦
but forget about it.
可是不用这么介意啦
Even if Hattori has a first love,
就算服部有初恋情人
that's already a thing of the past.
那也已经是过去的事情了
And you two look like you're in a stable relationship.
现在和你看上去感觉很要好啊
But first love is very special for men.
可是对于男人来说初恋是很特别的
Sonoko.
园子
Forget about it. Let's not talk about something so depressing.
算了  我们别提这种扫兴的事了
By the way, have some red bean soup.
对了  喝点红豆汤吧
Boss, we want three bowls of red bean soup. Be quick please.
老板娘  我们要三碗红豆汤  快一点哦
There is the west gate of Kurama Temple.
那里就是鞍马寺的西门了
Although usually you should go in through the Nio Gate,
虽然一般都该从仁王门进去
this is a shortcut.
但是这里是近路
(Kurama Temple  Inner Temple  588 meters)
[鞍马寺  内院  588米]
(Immobile Hall of Sojyougatani) This is the Immobile Hall of Sojyougatani.
[僧上谷不动堂]
Ushiwakamaru learned Kendo here from Tengu.
牛若丸就是在这里向天狗学到的剑法
This is really a good place for practicing kendo.
这里的确很适合练习剑道啊
This cedar tree is really big.
这棵杉树还真是大啊
Hattori, it's not here either.
服部  这里也不是
Get down.
趴下
Stop.
站住
Kudo.
工藤
This guy is just like Ushiwakamaru.
这家伙简直就像牛若丸一样
Darn.
糟了
Kudo, catch it. Let's go!
工藤  接着  我们追
Almost there!
就快追上了
That's harsh.
太狠了吧
(Kurama Temple)
[鞍马寺]
(Kurama Temple Station)
[鞍马车站]
Passengers, please get in the train as soon as possible.
坐车的乘客请赶快上车
The train is about to depart.
马上就要开车了
Don't have to be in such a hurry.
也不用这么急吧
This is a railway track.
这里可是铁轨啊
Don't talk to me, or I'll be distracted.
别和我说话  会分心的
Violation of the traffic law.
违反道路交通法
You'll definitely get your license revoked this time.
这下肯定被吊销执照哦
What is he going to do?
他打算干嘛
Damn it.
可恶
I literally almost caught up.
明明只差一点就追到了
That guy should be the murderer
那家伙应该
who killed Genjibotaru, right?
就是杀害源氏萤成员的凶手吧
Probably.
可能吧
But I don't know why he attacked you.
可是不知道他为什么会袭击你
Hattori,
服部
why are you here?
你为什么会在这里
I ran into Kudo on the street.
在街上偶然碰到了工藤
I mean, this kid.
啊不  这个小鬼
And we wanted to solve the riddle in the painting together.
想一起解开画里的谜题
So has the riddle in the painting been solved?
那么  画里的谜题解开了吗
Not yet, it's hard.
还没  很难啊
By the way, did uncle solve it?
对了  叔叔他解开了吗
Speaking of this,
说到这个嘛
♪ Korekawa Chiaki on the pillow ♪
(枕上是川千鸟)
(Ponto-cho)
[先斗町]
♪ Really miss Gion ♪ (Teahouse "Sakura House")
(真是怀念祗园) [茶屋『樱屋』]
(Kayoichi Geisha)
[市佳代  艺妓] (真是怀念祗园)
♪ Belt hanging down ♪
(垂下来的腰带) [市佳代  艺妓]
(Suzu Chika, 19, Geisha)
[千贺铃(19)  舞妓]
That's great. Ms. Suzu Chika is truly the number one in Japan.
太棒了  千贺铃小姐真是日本第一
It's a great honor to hear that you like it.
您能够喜欢真是太荣幸了
Then come and pour wine for Mr. Mouri.
那就快来给毛利先生斟酒
Right away.
好的
Please enjoy.
您请用
My Mouri seems to have climbed to heaven.
我小五郎就像爬上了天国啊
Go ahead and try to climb.
你倒是爬上去试试啊
Why are you guys here?
你们几个怎么来了
The Chief Priest told us about it.
是住持告诉我们的
Oh, it's the Chief Priest.
原来是住持说的啊
Then would you like to join us?
那么各位也一起来吧
Sorry to interrupt.
对不起  打扰了
Hey, aren't you from Miyagawa...
咦  你不就是宫川町的...
Yes, I'm Suzu Chika.
是啊  我是千贺铃
I owe you for that one time.
那个时候多亏您了
Do you know, Heiji?
你认识吗  平次
Kind of.
算是吧
You create trouble when no one notices, seriously.
真是的  一不注意你就乱来
Ran,
小兰小姐
don't blame your father.
你就不要怪你爸爸了
I invited him to come.
是我约他来的嘛
Yeah,
是啊
we wanted the renowned detective to help us
想让名侦探帮我们
with investigating the Genjibotaru's case together.
推理一下源氏萤的案件呢
(Sakura House's owner) Speaking of the members of Genjibotaru,
说到源氏萤的成员
it seems that everyone has a copy of "Chronicles of Yoshitsune".
好像每个人都有本《义经记》呢
I have one, too. It's a good book.
我也有啊  那可是本好书
Right, bookstore boss?
对吧  古书老板
Yes, but I don't like that book very much.
是啊  可是我不是很喜欢那本书
Although the name is "Chronicles of Yoshitsune",
名字虽说是《义经记》
it's all about Benkei's deeds.
可完全就是记录弁庆事迹的
It should be called "Benkeiji".
应该叫《弁庆记》才对
But I like it.
可是我喜欢啊
Especially Benkei's story in Ataka. That's the best.
特别是安宅里的弁庆最棒了
What is Ataka?
安宅是什么
It's a play of Noh theatre.
是能剧的一个剧目
In order to escape Yorimoto's pursuit,
为了能逃脱赖朝的追缉
Yoshitsune and the family members disguised as monks
义经和家将们化装成修行僧
to pass the checkpoint at Anzaka.
想要通过安宅的关口
Just when Yoshitsune's disguise was about to be seen through,
正当义经的化装就快被拆穿的时候
Benkei acted within a split second and beat Yoshitsune.
弁庆灵机一动用金刚棒打了义经
Why?
为什么
To deceive the guards at the checkpoint.
为了骗过关口的看守
Because no one would have thought that the subordinate would beat his master.
因为谁都不会想到家将会打自己的主君
Then Yoshitsune and his party passed the checkpoint smoothly.
然后义经一行平安的通过了关口
Afterwards, Benkei cried and apologized to Yoshitsune.
事后弁庆哭着向义经谢罪
Unexpectedly, Yoshitsune praised Benkei for his wit.
没想到义经却称赞弁庆的机智
From then on, the master and subordinate had a deep connection.
从此知道了主仆二人的感情深厚
And the story went on as a legend.
传为佳话
I'm sorry. I've been having trouble sleeping lately.
不好意思  最近我总是失眠
I want to rest for a while in the room down there.
我想在下面的房间稍微休息一会儿
We don't have guests coming in tonight.
今晚也不会有其他客人来
You can go to the room next door.
您可以去隔壁的房间
It's alright. The room down there will do.
不用了  下面的房间就可以
Please wake me up at 9 o'clock.
那么请你在9点叫醒我
Everyone, please have fun.
大家就请尽情的玩吧
We can see the river.
可以看见河呢
It's Kamogawa.
是鸭川
The cherry blossoms are so beautiful.
樱花好美啊
Yeah.
真的呢
Ran, come and have a look.
小兰你也过来看看嘛
It's nice to view cherry blossom in pairs on the Kamogawa River,
在鸭川河畔成双成对的赏樱很有情调
but enjoying the cherry blossoms across the Misogi River that surrounds this building
不过像这样隔着环绕这幢建筑的禊河赏樱
also feels quite special.
也别有一番风味哟
Yeah, really beautiful.
真的  好漂亮
It is good indeed.
是漂亮啊
It's almost like a delicacy.
简直像凝脂一样
I really want to eat it.
真想吃下去了呢
Are you hurt?
受了伤吗
Yeah, a little bit.
是啊  一点点
Let me help you.
我来帮你治好
That's too much.
你不要太过分了
Creepy old man.
好色的老头
Hey, look.
喂  你看那儿
Inspector Ayanokoji.
绫小路警部
What is he doing there?
他在那儿做什么啊
You can go to the terrace below
你们可以去下面的露台上
to see the cherry blossoms at night.
看看夜晚的樱花
After the clouds clear tonight,
今晚等云层散去后
the moon will show its beauty.
会有很美的月亮哦
Let's go and check it out.
我们去看看吧
Great.
太好了
I'll stay here.
我就呆在这里
Me, too.
我也是
Why?
为什么
Do you care about that geisha?
是不是很关心那个舞妓啊
Idiot, what nonsense are you talking about?
白痴  胡说什么呢
I lost.
我输了
Uncle is really going all out.
大叔还真是全力以赴啊
He has always been like this.
他一直都这样的啦
Suzu Chika, one more time.
千贺铃  再来
Do it again.
再来一次啦
I'd like to use the restroom.
我要去一下厕所
It's okay. I'm not drunk yet.
没关系  我还没醉呢
Just stay with Mr. Mouri.
你就陪着毛利先生吧
OK.
好的
Okay, let's start.
好  开始了哟
The moon is out.
月亮出来了
The moon.
月亮
What's wrong?
怎么了
It reminds me of the date I had with Ran before.
我想起了以前和小兰约好见面的事情了
That day, when I remembered I had a date,
那次我想起约会的时候
I was already two hours late.
已经迟到两个小时了
That's too crazy.
太夸张了吧
I thought she had left.
我想她也许已经走了
But I still went to our meet-up point to check.
但我还是跑到约会的地方去看看
Who is it?
谁
I'm sorry, I totally...
对不起  其实我完全...
It's great.
太好了
I was worried that
我还一直在担心你
something might've happened to you.
会不会出了什么事
Was that when you realized
就是那个时候吧
that she's more than a childhood friend?
发现她已不仅仅是青梅竹马了
Idiot, there is no such thing.
笨蛋  没有这回事啦
I have long discovered that she's more than a childhood friend.
我早就发现她不只是青梅竹马了
She's probably still waiting for me.
她到现在都还在等着我吧
What's wrong, Ran?
怎么了  小兰
Nothing.
没什么
Heiji is really irritating.
平次这家伙真让人生气
But Toyama, I'm so jealous of you.
可是和叶我好羡慕你
Because you can see each other when you want to.
因为想见的时候就可以见到啊
Ran.
小兰
Yes, I rarely get to see Kyogoku, too.
是啊  我也一直见不到阿真
The troubles of girls are endless.
少女的烦恼真是无穷啊
In comparison, the uncles are really energetic.
相比起来大叔们还真是精力旺盛啊
Mr. Sakura, it's 9 o'clock.
樱先生  已经九点了
Mr. Sakura.
樱先生
Please excuse me.
打扰了
Where did he go?
到哪儿去了
That's strange.
真是奇怪
Mr. Sakura?
樱先生
What's with the scream just now?
怎么了  刚才的惨叫
Someone, help!
来人啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
Mr. Sakura…
樱先生他
No one is allowed in.
谁都不许进来
Ran, call the police.
小兰  打电话报警
Sure.
是
The carotid artery was slashed with a sharp weapon.
是用锋利的刀割断了颈动脉
The cut is perfect.
切口很完美
Should be the same murderer as the serial-killer case.
这和连续凶杀案应该是同一个凶手
I keep thinking that I've met you somewhere.
我总觉得在哪里看到过你
Are you the junior detective,
是高中生侦探
Heiji Hattori?
服部平次吗
Yes.
是的
Before the police arrive, please wait in your rooms.
在警察来之前大家都到刚才的房间去等着吧
Do not come out.
绝对不可以出去
Got it.
知道了
Mr. Sakura seems to have gotten killed
樱先生好像是
while looking for something in the warehouse.
在仓库里找什么东西的时候被杀的
What was he looking for?
到底在找什么呢
The button of the coat got torn off,
上衣的扣子被扯掉了
probably because there were gloves on
可能因为用带手套的手
so it'd be too much trouble to unbutton it.
解开扣子太麻烦了
But the wallet filled with money is still here,
可是装满钞票的钱包又没事
so it's not for money.
可见不是为了钱财
Don't touch the body.
不许碰遗体
How many times do I have to say this for you to understand?
要说多少次你才懂啊
Ouch!
好痛啊
I'm Ayanokoji from the Kyoto Police Department.
我是京都警府的绫小路
Thank you for your hard work. Please come in.
辛苦你们了  请进
You guard the door.
你守在门口
Roger that.
是
Isn't this a police officer in Kyoto?
这不是京都的警官吗
You got here so fast.
你来的还真快啊
Where's your chipmunk?
喂  你的松鼠呢
I don't always take it with me.
我又不会总是把它带在身边
What do you think? Did someone outside do it?
你怎么看  是外面的人干的吗
We can't eliminate the possibility,
虽然不能说完全不可能
but if the door was opened and made a sound,
但是如果大门被打开发出了声音
the owner would have noticed,
老板娘应该会注意到
Besides,
而且
the murderer knew that Mr. Sakura
凶手又知道樱先生
would go to the warehouse for some reason.
为了某个理由会去仓库
In other words,
也就是说
he probably knew Mr. Sakura,
很有可能是认识樱先生的
Saijo, Ryuen, Mizuo and the others.
西条  龙圆  水尾他们了
The three of them
三个人在
have been to the bathroom
樱先生和小兰他们离开后
after Mr. Sakura and Ran left.
都各去过一次厕所
There is also a staircase leading to the basement next to it.
而且旁边就有通向地下室的楼梯
This means that the three could have gone to the warehouse and killed Mr. Sakura
也就是说三个人都有可能在假装上厕所的时候
when they pretended to go to the bathroom.
到楼下的仓库来杀害樱先生
But one thing feels out of place.
但是有一件事觉得不太对劲
Why did Suzu Chika go with Mizuo
为什么水尾去上厕所的时候
to the bathroom?
千贺铃要陪着他呢
The geishas seem to do that.
舞妓们好像都是这么做的
But she didn't do that with Ryuen and Saijo.
但是她又没有陪龙圆和西条
That's because she happened to be playing a game with my uncle.
那是因为正好在和叔叔玩游戏啦
We can also say that
反过来说他们
they might have specifically picked that time to go to the bathroom.
也有可能特地找这个时间来上厕所
If that's the case,
这样的话
the murderer is either Ryuen or Saijo.
凶手就是龙圆或者西条
If Suzu Chika is not an accomplice,
水尾应该是清白的了
then Mizuo should be innocent.
如果千贺铃不是共犯的话
Yes.
是啊
Then let's go.
那么我们走吧
Stop pretending.
不要装蒜了
Did you find something in Mr. Sakura's upper pocket?
你在樱先生的上衣口袋里找到了什么吧
Well.
这个啊
Mr. Sakura's shop should be on Teramachi Street, right?
樱先生的店应该是在寺町路吧
(Sakura Antique Shop)
[樱古美术店]
Gikeki.
义经记
Iseno Saburo.
伊势三郎
Hattori.
服部
What? Mr. Sakura is Iseno Saburo?
什么  樱先生就是伊势三郎啊
What is this?
这是什么
This is...
这是...
a copy of the painting.
那幅画的复印件
What is going on?
到底是怎么回事
Mr. Sakura also had this painting, which means
樱先生同样有这幅画也就是说
the letter was sent by Mr. Sakura to Sannou Temple.
那封信就是樱先生寄到山能寺的
But for what?
不过是为了什么呢
What?
什么
Mr. Sakura was Iseno Saburo.
樱先生就是伊势三郎
Yes, it looks like he was a member of Genjibotaru.
是啊  他好像也是源氏萤的成员
Wait a minute, the one who got killed is...
等一下  这样被杀害的是...
Could the next one be me, the one they missed?
难道说下一个就是被漏掉的我
If this is the case, it should've happened a long time ago.
这样的话应该早就被杀掉了
If the painting in Mr. Sakura's house
如果说樱先生家里的那幅画
is a copy of the original,
是复印件的话
wouldn't it be very likely that Mr. Sakura carried the original with him
那不是很有可能樱先生随身带着原件
and it got taken away by the murderer?
然后被凶手拿走了吗
I see.
原来如此
The murderer didn't expect Mr. Sakura to keep a copy in advance.
凶手没有想到樱先生会事先留有复印件
So who is the murderer?
那么凶手究竟是谁啊
I think the murderer is among Mr. Ryuen, Mr. Saijo.
我认为是龙圆先生  西条先生
Mr. Mizuo and Ms. Suzu Chika.
水尾先生和千贺铃小姐中的某个人
But none of them had a weapon with them.
可是他们谁都没有带着凶器啊
After the two of you left,
你们两个离开后
the police did a search.
警方就搜过身了
How could someone still carry a weapon
怎么会有杀了人
after killing someone?
还把凶器带在身上的白痴啊
It must have been thrown away or hidden.
肯定是扔掉或是藏起来了吧
But it wasn't found in the store either.
可是在店里也没有找到
How about the Misogi River?
禊河里呢
Could it be thrown out of the glass window in the basement?
会不会是从地下室的玻璃窗扔出去了
Right? I think so, too.
对吧  我也是这样想的
Suzuki said she heard
园子说她听到了
the sound of something falling into the Misogi River.
什么东西掉进禊河的声音
Really?
真的吗
Yes, but the police searched the river
没错  可是警察搜查了这条河
and found nothing.
什么都没找到
That's strange.
真是奇怪啊
In this case, there must be an accomplice.
这样的话就一定有共犯
The accomplice outside picked up the murder weapon from the river.
在外面的共犯把凶器从河里捡走了
This is impossible.
这是不可能的
Why? Ku…Conan.
为什么啊  工...啊不  柯南
It's a full moon tonight, so it's very bright outside.
今晚是满月  外面很亮的啊
The balcony floor has a gap that allows one to see the river below.
而且那阳台地板上有缝能看到下面的河
If there is an accomplice over there,
如果禊河那边有共犯的话
Ran-chan and the others should've noticed.
小兰姐姐她们应该会注意到的
That's true.
也是啊
The truth is,
真相是这样的
the murderer is someone outside.
凶手是外面的人
Before Ran and the others got to the balcony,
在小兰她们到阳台之前
the murderer went in from the glass window downstairs,
从楼下的玻璃窗进入
hid in a place somewhere like the bathroom,
然后躲在浴室之类的地方埋伏着
killed Mr. Sakura while he came in looking for something,
趁樱先生进来找东西的时候把他杀害了
and then ran away with the murder weapon through the glass window.
然后就带着凶器从玻璃窗逃走了
But none of us saw anyone suspicious.
可是我们都没有看到可疑的人
There are no witnesses by the riverbank either.
河堤上也没有目击者啊
It's a coincidence.
偶然啦偶然
The murderer had better luck.
凶手的运气比较好
I feel like something's not right.
总感觉有点不对劲啊
That guy is from Mount Kurama...
那家伙  就是鞍马山上的...
Toyama, don't let go!
和叶  千万不要松手啊
What?
什么
Stay here, okay?
你待在这里  知道吗
Heiji!
平次
Do you want to have a showdown with me? That works.
是想要和我一决胜负吗  没问题
What? There are flaws everywhere.
什么嘛  到处都是破绽
Wearing a wristband.
戴着护腕啊
Are you the murderer who killed Mr. Sakura?
你就是杀了樱先生的凶手吧
Then try it here just like back then.
那么就像那时一样刺这里试试
This is not what you want.
这不是你想要的东西
I can't see clearly anymore.
眼睛看不清了
Inspector, here!
警官  这里这里
Heiji! Are you okay?
平次没事吧
Toyama, where's the police?
和叶  警察呢
It was obviously a bluff.
明摆着是唬人的啦
Where did you learn this?
你从哪里学来的这手
What a terrible woman.
真是可怕的女人啊
Heiji.
平次
(Umekouji Hospital)
[梅小路医院]
Heiji, you're awake.
平次  你醒了
Toyama.
和叶
Thank God.
太好了
Worried us to death, Heiji.
让人担心死了  平次
Inspector Otaki.
大泷警官
And, who are you again?
还有  你是谁来着
I am Shiratori from the Police Department.
我是警视厅的白鸟
I heard that Shozo Sakura who got killed was a member of Genjibotaru,
听说被杀害的樱正造是源氏萤的成员
so I rushed over from Tokyo.
我就从东京赶来了
Does it still hurt?
还痛吗
A little.
有一点
The stolen art was found in Sakura's shop.
从樱正造店里找到了被偷的美术品
Are you awake?
你醒过来了吗
Inspector, where's the short knife?
警部先生  那把短刀呢
It's going under tests.
现在正在化验
Tell me immediately when the result comes out.
结果出来马上告诉我
If the evidence is not enough,
如果证据还不够的话
you can use the wound on my shoulder as well.
我肩膀上的伤口也提供给你
What evidence?
什么证据
The evidence to prove that the short knife
证明那把短刀是
is the murder weapon that killed Mr. Sakura.
杀害樱先生的凶器的证据
Actually, it'll be great if someone had come into contact
其实如果有接触到凶手的
with the murderer's skin.
皮肤的东西就最好了
What about the motorcycle? Isn't there a motorcycle?
摩托车  还有摩托车
That was a stolen one.
那辆是已经报失的车
The evidence to find the murderer.
是找出凶手的证据
Also, do you understand what this painting means now?
另外  这张画你们明白是什么意思了吗
It was tuck into Mr. Sakura's "Chronicles of Yoshitsune".
就是夹在樱先生的《义经记》里的
Are you sure you don't know?
真的不知道吗
Don't worry then.
不知道就算了
Just stay put then.
那么你就老老实实的呆着吧
I'll be going as well.
那我也告辞了
Take care and feel better soon, Heiji.
好好养病啊  平次
I'll give dad a call.
我去给爸爸打个电话
Let me ask the doctor for you.
我去帮您问一下医生吧
Conan is with me.
和柯南在一起
Ran.
小兰
I'll go out for a bit. please take care of Heiji.
我稍微出去一下  平次就拜托你了
Is it okay? Why don't you stay in the hospital to recover?
没关系吗  不呆在医院静养
It's okay.
没关系啦
But that guy is really strange.
不过那家伙真的很奇怪
I've never seen that kind of swordsmanship.
我第一次见到那样的剑法
He might have added steel bars to the wristband.
可能是在护腕里加上了钢筋
I wanted to use the wound to find the murder weapon.
而且我本想用伤口来找出凶器
That's why I got myself a cut by the short knife.
所以才故意让短刀划了一下
I didn't expect him to drop the knife.
没想到他把刀扔下了
Why is that?
这是为什么
Also,
还不止呢
while we were fighting,
那家伙在打斗的途中
the guy actually wanted to pick up this sachet that I dropped.
居然想捡起我掉下来的这个香袋
All things that one can't figure out.
尽是些想不通的事情
Could the one wearing an old man's mask
该不会那个戴老翁面具的
be your first love?
就是你的初恋情人吧
You have a point.
也是啊
How could there be such a thing?
怎么可能有这种事
(Mizuo's House)
[水尾宅]
You were attacked later.
你后来被袭击了
I'm sorry but,
虽然很失礼
I wanted to ask about Mr. Mizuo's alibi.
我想问一下水尾先生的不在场证明
The murderer wore the mask of the old man in Noh theatre.
因为凶手戴着能剧里的老翁面具
Old man's mask.
老翁的面具
Also, Mr. Saijo
顺便也问一下西条先生
and Mr. Ryuen's alibis would be greatly appreciated as well.
和龙圆先生的不在场证明
We have to be questioned, too?
我们也要问啊
Seriously?
真是的
I came here today to talk about the murderer of Mr. Sakura
我今天来本来是想和千贺铃小姐
with Suzu Chika in a party of four.
四个人一起讨论杀害樱先生的凶手的
Right?
对吧
It's okay. I went straight home to sleep right after yesterday.
没关系  昨天结束后我就直接回家睡觉了
But I'm still single,
但是我还是单身
and my room is far from my mom's room.
而且我的房间和母亲的房间离得很远
I can't prove whether I've been at home all that time.
也无法证明那以后我是否一直在家
Same here.
我也差不多
I live alone on the second floor of the store on Teramachi Street.
一个人住在寺町街店里的二楼
After I returned to the temple,
我回到寺里后
I read the scriptures in the main hall for a while. Then I fell asleep.
在大殿里看了一会儿经文就睡觉了
No witnesses.
也没有证人
I see.
是这样啊
I have another question.
我还有个问题
Has anyone practiced archery?
各位有谁练过射箭吗
Archery? No.
射箭吗  没有
I once used a Catalpa Bow for the Noh play called "Appreciating the Fallen Leaves".
我曾在名为《赏红叶》的能剧里拉过梓木弓
I once used the bow and arrow to disperse evil spirits.
我曾经试过拉响弓弦来做法事驱散恶灵
So was there anyone in the tea house that knew archery?
那么当时在茶屋中的人中有谁是会射箭的吗
Sounds like Yamakura.
这样说的话好像山仓
(Tae Yamakura) But she wasn't present at the time.
可是当时她不在场啊
Oh no...
啊不...
Excuse me.
打扰了
She is coming.
她来了
What?
咦
What's wrong?
怎么了
Please.
请请
Are you Miss Suzu Chika?
大姐姐就是千贺铃小姐吗
Yes.
是啊
You must be surprised by how different she looks.
和舞妓打扮简直判若两人  很吃惊吧
Please come in.
请进
OK, thanks.
好的  多谢
Thanks for visiting last night.
谢谢昨晚的光顾
Please come back again.
以后也请多多捧场
Don't mention it.
哪里哪里
Thanks, bye.
谢谢  再见
Sannou Temple is on Rokkaku street.
山能寺是在六角街上的
This is Ebisu Avenue.
这里是夷街
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹  夷二  押御池
Ane-San-Rokkaku…
姐姐  六角...
So it should be the sixth street.
所以该是第六条街
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹  夷二  押御池
What's the song you just sang now?
刚才你唱的是什么歌
We call it the Temari song.
我们叫它手球歌
It's a song made up with all the major roads in Kyoto that run east to west
是把京都所有东西向的街道名称
appearing in the order of north to south.
从北至南串了起来
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹  夷二  押御池
Ane-San-Rokkaku-Tako-Nishiki
姐姐  六角  蛸锦
Shi-Aya-Butsu-Taka-Matsu-Man-Gojo
四绫佛  高松  万五条
Setta-Chara, chara-Uonotana
雪靴  叮叮当当  鱼架
through Rokujo-Santetsu
走过六条街和七条街
after Shichijo comes Hachi-Kujo
过了八条街就是东寺道
Kujo, toji comes at the end
穿过九条大街就到了
Kids in Kyoto
京都的小孩
all sing this song to remember the names of the streets in Kyoto.
都唱这首歌来记住京都的路名
Then you are also from Kyoto.
那么你也是京都人了
Yes.
是啊
How old are you?
几岁了
19 years old.
19岁
Then this is Oike Street.
这里就是御池街了
I'll be going.
我先告辞了
Goodbye.
再见
Are you thinking that she is…
你该不会认为她就是
Absolutely right.
绝对没错
She was born in Kyoto and is two years older than me.
京都出身  年纪比我大两岁
But don't the kids in Kyoto all sing that song?
可是京都的小孩不是都会唱那首歌吗
I've reunited with her at last.
终于见到她了  终于
Hey.
喂喂
Heiji, what are you doing?
平次你在干什么
It's ridiculous to leave the hospital like this.
自己跑出医院也太胡来了
Officer Otaki.
大泷警官
(Kyoto Prefecture Police) Let's not talk about this yet.
[京都府警]
The results of the blood test came out.
血液化验的结果出来了 [京都府警]
The blood on the handle of the short knife
短刀刀柄上的血迹
is found to be of the same blood type as that of Mr. Sakura's.
化验出来和樱先生的血型一致
The marks that the sword left are the same as the marks on Sakura's body as well.
而且刀口同樱先生的伤口也一致
Really?
是吗
Heiji, I've told you the results.
平次  虽然结果是告诉你了
But don't you mess around.
你可别乱来啊
If anything happens to you,
万一你出了什么事
I won't know what to say to your dad...
我可没有办法向你父亲...
I got it.
我知道啦
Thank you, Inspector Otaki.
谢谢啦  大泷警官
So it seems that the person who attacked me
如此看来袭击我的凶手
is the murderer who killed Mr. Sakura.
和杀害樱先生的凶手肯定是同一个人
So those four people who couldn't get rid of the weapon couldn't be the murderer.
那么无法处理凶器的那四个人就不是凶手了
Conan, what are you doing?
柯南  你在干嘛
Why are you guys here?
你们几个怎么来了
We solved the riddle of the Doctor,
我们答对了博士的问题
so he brought us to Kyoto.
所以他就带我们来京都了
But Genta
可是元太他
got lost.
迷了路
Then use the detective badge.
那就用侦探徽章啊
I've called him, and we've been in touch,
已经呼叫他了  都联系上了
but Genta doesn't understand Kanji characters
可是元太不认识汉字
so he can't tell us where he is now.
说不出来现在在哪里
So I wanted to use your glasses to find him.
所以想用你的那个眼镜来找一下
OK, leave it to me.
OK  就交给我吧
This is interesting, there.
这个有意思  在那里
Yeah.
真是的
There seems to be a case in your area, too.
你这里好像也发生了案件啊
Yes, I will tell you the details later.
是啊  详细情况等会儿再和你说
Wait a minute, Ai, give me the medicine.
等一下  小哀  把那药给我
What's that?
那是什么
Hunger suppressing medicine.
抑制肚子叫的药
It's developed by the doctor for those attending wedding and funeral banquets.
是博士给参加婚葬宴会的人专门开发的
For those who can't drink,
还有为那些不能喝酒的人发明的
there's a medication that turns one's face red immediately.
吃下去脸马上就红的药
For those who want to take time off,
还有给那些想请假的人
there's a medication that shows symptoms of a bad cold immediately after taking it.
吃下去马上就出现重感冒症状的药
These are all developed by Ai.
这些都是小哀帮忙开发的哦
So these are useless.
这些都根本用不上啊
(Rokkaku Temple) It's here. This is Rokkaku.
[六角堂]
He's here!
他在这儿啊
Great!
太好了
Mother.
妈妈
Genta is there.
元太在那里
I'm saved!
得救了
Great, Genta!
太好了  元太
I thought I would never see you again in my lifetime!
我还以为这辈子都见不到你了
Me, too.
我也是啊
But this thing is really convenient,
不过这东西还真是方便啊
the badge with a signal sensor.
附有发信器的徽章
Yeah!
是啊
The frequency of the signal from this transmitter is the same as that of the glasses.
这个发信器发出来的信号频率和这幅眼镜一致
Hattori.
服部
I see.
是这样啊
What's up?
干什么啊
Kudo, could it be?
工藤  难道说
It must be.
肯定没错了
Yes.
是啊
What the lady heard was indeed the sound of the murder weapon falling into the river.
那位小姐听到的确实是凶器掉进河里的声音
So the murderer is indeed one of those four people.
那么凶手还是那四个人中间的一个
No, one of those three.
不对  是三个人
How could my first love be a murderer?
我的初恋情人怎么可能是杀人凶手呢
Here we go again.
又来了
But there is still something I find strange.
但是有件事我还是觉得奇怪
The song I just heard is different from the one I remember.
刚才听到的歌和我记忆中的有个地方不一样
My first love
我的初恋情人
sang "Yome-san-Rokkaku" instead of "Ane-san-Rokkaku".
唱的是“新娘六角”而不是“姐姐六角”
Why is that?
这是为什么呢
How would I know?
我怎么知道
Found it! The broken pieces of the mask.
找到了  面具的碎片
Police Department,
警部
What are you thinking?
您在想什么呢
Is it this one?
是这个吗
Things worn on the three people killed in Tokyo.
在东京被杀害的三人身上戴的东西
One was wearing a hat; one was wearing a scarf.
一个人是戴帽子  一个人是戴围巾
And another was wearing gloves.
还有一个人是戴手套
The colors, styles, and textures are the same.
颜色款式和质地都一样
Don't you think it's weird?
不觉得很奇怪吗
Really strange.
确实奇怪
What's weird?
哪儿奇怪啊
For example, if Shiratori wore these three by himself, then it'd feel normal.
比如说如果白鸟他一个人戴着这三样就很自然
But if Inspector Megure wore this hat,
但是如果目暮警官戴着这顶帽子
and I wore this scarf,
我围着这条围巾
then Takagi wore these gloves,
高木戴着这双手套
wouldn't you think it's weird?
不觉得很奇怪吗
Indeed.
的确是
It literally feels like Shiratori was dead,
简直好像是白鸟死了
and the three of us divided his belongings.
我们三个人分了他的遗物似的
That's it.
就是这样
What's going on?
怎  怎么回事
I'm hungry.
肚子饿了
Bear with it.
忍一下啦
Suzu Chika's mom worked as a geisha in Miyagawa.
千贺铃的母亲在宫川町做艺妓
She died of an illness when Suzu Chika was five years old.
在她五岁的时候病死了
And she was a single mother.
而且还是未婚妈妈
Later, Suzu Chika was adopted by the teahouse owner, Yamakura,
后来千贺铃被茶屋老板娘山仓收养了
and she was raised by Yamakura.
由她抚养长大
What does a single mother mean?
未婚妈妈是什么意思
I was wondering the same thing.
就是说
A woman who gives birth to a child without getting married?
没结婚就生下孩子的女人
Although I don't know who her father is,
虽然不知道她的父亲是谁
there was money sent to her anonymously every month.
不过每个月都匿名给她寄钱
But for some reason it suddenly stopped three months ago.
但是三个月前不知道为什么突然停止了
It is quite perplexing indeed.
的确有一些令人疑惑的地方
Three months ago?
从三个月以前
But how did you find out about this, Inspector Shiratori?
但是白鸟警部你是从哪里打听来的
Did you learn about it from Inspector Ayanakoji?
从绫小路警部那里听来的吧
No.
不是
Don't underestimate me.
不要小瞧人
I've got my ways in Gion.
我在祗园可是很有名气的
Is that something to be proud of?
这也值得骄傲啊
Although that guy is my opponent,
虽然那家伙被称为是我的死对头
I don't want to be compared with someone who always carries a chipmunk.
不过我才不想和总是带着松鼠的人相提并论...
Chipmunk?
松鼠
He always has it in his pocket.
他都放在口袋里的
At least he didn't bring it to the scene of the crime.
不过在案发现场没带
Chipmunk?
松鼠
This is Inspector Shiratori.
是  我是白鸟
This is Megure.
我是目暮
Another possibility emerged in the Benkei and Yoshitsune case.
关于弁庆和义经一案又出现了一个可能性
Belongings.
分遗物留念
If you think about it this way, the riddle will be solved.
这样想的话谜题就解开了
In other words, we reasoned that Benkei or Yoshitsune might be dead already.
也就是说我们推理出弁庆或义经可能已经死了
I see!
我知道了
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
Do you really know who murdered Mr. Sakura?
你真的知道杀害樱先生的凶手是谁了吗
Yes
是的
Now, please listen.
接下来请听我说
The murderer is you, Ms. Suzu Chika.
凶手就是你  千贺铃小姐
Nonsense!
少胡说八道
What a mess!
尽是乱七八糟的推理
Is he okay?
他没问题的吧
Anyway, let him finish first.
总之先听他说完
The motive is to avenge your father who got killed.
动机是为被杀害的父亲报仇
Your father is Yoshitsune, the leader of the gang of robbers.
而且你的父亲就是盗贼团的首领义经
Yoshitsune was killed by his men who betrayed him three months ago,
义经在三个月之前遭背叛的部下杀害
so the money that got sent to Suzu Chika also stopped.
所以寄给千贺铃的钱也停止了
I see.
原来如此
You have another accomplice,
然后你还有一个共犯
Benkei.
就是弁庆
Benkei?
弁庆
Who is this Benkei?
这个弁庆到底是谁呢
Inspector Ayanokoji.
绫小路警部
It's you.
就是你
Ms. Suzu Chika, when you went to the teahouse,
千贺铃小姐你到茶屋的时候
you had something with you.
身上带了某个东西
The dagger and the chipmunk raised by Inspector Ayanakoji.
那就是短刀和绫小路警部养的那只松鼠
So cute!
好可爱啊
This chipmunk is the key to the crime.
这只松鼠是犯罪手法的关键
Ms. Suzu Chika, you pretended to go to the bathroom in the middle of the banquet,
千贺铃小姐你在宴会中间假装去厕所
and went on to kill Mr. Sakura in the warehouse.
然后在仓库里杀害了樱先生
You tied the short knife on the chipmunk that hid there in advance,
再将短刀绑在事先藏在那里的松鼠身上
and then let it out from the glass window.
把它从玻璃窗放出去
The chipmunk jumped into the river and swam to the lower reaches of the river,
松鼠跳到河里后  游到河的下游
where Inspector Ayanokoji awaited to retrieve the knife.
然后等在那里的绫小路警部将刀回收
He then used this knife to attack Heiji.
再用这把短刀去袭击平次
I see!
是这样啊
So that splashing sound was caused by the chipmunk jumping into the water.
原来那个水声就是松鼠跳进水的声音啊
Other than the case of Mr. Sakura, the other two crimes were also committed by the two of you.
除樱先生以外的案子也是你们两个人共同犯下的
Inspector, do you know archery?
警部先生  你会射箭吧
For something so troublesome, how would I know it?
这种麻烦的事情我怎么可能会
Is that so?
是真的吗
But Ms. Suzu Chika,
可是千贺铃小姐
I heard that people who practice archery
听说练习射箭的人
often get themselves injured at this very spot.
这里很容易被箭头擦到而受伤的
It's true.
的确是这样
This wound of mine indeed came from archery practice,
我箭枕的伤口确实是因为练射箭的关系
but I just started learning it.
可是我刚刚才开始学
How could I possibly kill someone with it?
怎么可能杀得了人呢
That's what I thought, too.
我也是这样想的
This should be proof that she's a beginner because she has a wound near her thumb.
这里会受伤应该是初学者的证明啊
I heard this from my friends in the archery club.
我听弓箭部的朋友说的
And the deceased had no reason to divide the belongings.
而且死者也没有分遗物的理由
Mr. Mouri,
毛利先生
do you really think that this girl is a murderer?
你该不是真的把这孩子当作凶手吧
Well...
那个  因为...
Stop joking.
少开玩笑了
This kid is very busy with singing, dancing and tea ceremony,
这孩子要练习歌舞和茶道可是很忙的
where does she get the time to kill?
哪有空去杀人啊
What?
干嘛
That chipmunk,
松鼠啊
I'm afraid it can't carry a short knife with such a small body.
那么小的身体恐怕背不动短刀的吧
So annoying.
啰嗦
I'll prove it to you.
那我就证明给你们看看
Move, chipmunk.
快动啊  松鼠
I can't stand it anymore.
我都看不下去了
You are acting like this to get out of the crime, aren't you?
你是想脱罪才故意装成这样的吧
Stop it.
住手啦
Poor chipmunk, uncle.
松鼠太可怜了  大叔
This is animal cruelty.
这可是虐待动物哟
Shut up, you kids.
小鬼们给我闭嘴
Genta, save the chipmunk.
元太  快救松鼠
Okay.
好
Kudo.
工藤
Thanks to Uncle, I got the murderer now.
多亏了大叔  知道凶手是谁了
Me, too.
我也知道了
It had to be someone good at archery to say such a thing.
如果不是精于射箭是不会说出那样的话的
We just need evidence now.
现在就差证据
And the whereabouts of that Buddha statue.
以及佛像的所在了
Little chipmunk, poor baby.
小松鼠你真可怜
Let's feed it with something.
我们找点什么东西给它吃吧
I have an acorn.
我有橡栗哦
This feels like the children's song, "Donguri Koro Koro".
简直像歌里唱的咕噜咕噜滚的小橡栗
Donguri Koro Koro.
橡栗咕噜咕噜
Could it be...
难道是...
What's wrong, Kudo?
怎么了  工藤
It suddenly occurred to me that the copy of the painting might refer to the name of a street in Kyoto.
我突然想到那张复印的画可能是指京都的路名
What are you saying?
你说什么
The first is the east-west street.
首先是东西向的路
If the fifth floor is
这第五层就是五条街的话
(Fifth Street) the fifth street
[五条街]
and the fourth floor
第四层是四条街
Between the third floor and the second floor,
这第三层和第二层的中间
that's the middle of the third and second street.
就是在三条街和二条街当中的
(Oike Street) That's Oike Street.
[御池街]
Then the evidence for this is would be...
这样说的证据就是 [御池街]
Donguri Koro Koro.
橡栗咕噜咕噜
Then there is a north-south road.
接着是南北走向的路
(Ogawa Street) There is a song called "Ogawa Spring" that talks about violets.
有首叫《春之小川》的歌有提到紫罗兰
So it's Ogawa Street.
所以是小川街
(Karasuma Street) Tengu is mentioned in "Karasu Tengu".
“鸟天狗”中提到天狗 [小川街]
So it's Karasuma Street.
所以是鸟丸街 [鸟丸街]
(Mount Fuji) Then there is the character of Mt. Fuji,
然后是富士山的富字所以是富小路街
(Tominokoji Street) so it is Tominokoji Street.
[富小路街] 然后是富士山的富字所以是富小路街
What is that chicken?
那鸡又是什么
The loach is probably the "Yanagi Pot".
泥鳅恐怕是“柳川锅”
(Yanaginobanba Street) So it's Yanaginobanba Street?
[柳马场街]
Chicken is...
鸡是...
Isn't it Nishinotoin Street?
不是西洞院街吗
(Nishinotoin Street) Because the chicken head points to the west.
因为鸡头指向了西方
That's so hard.
这么难啊
And what's this?
那么这又是什么
The cicada is of the "large brown cicada",
蝉就是“油蝉”的蝉  所以是油小路街
(Aburanokoji Street) so it is Aburanokoji Street.
[油小路街]
(Youkoji Street) Tengu is Toromaru Street.
天狗是鸟丸街
Goldfish eats wheat bran,
金鱼的食物是麦麸  所以是麸屋町街
Then the violets and Mount Fuji share the same color.
然后同一个颜色的紫罗兰和富士山
Chicken and loach, cicada and goldfish
公鸡和泥鳅  蝉和金鱼
Then connect Tengu with Tengu.
再把天狗和天狗连起来
King? What's with this word "King"?
王字  这个王字又是什么
There's an extra dot.
还有一个点
It should be like this.
应该是这样的吧
Jade, meaning there's a treasure.
玉就是玉器  有宝石的意思
So this place is...
这个地方就是
Bukkoji Temple.
佛光寺
This is where we find the treasure.
这样我们就找到宝贝了
What's wrong?
怎么了
I'm feeling a bit dizzy.
有点头晕
(Rokkaku Temple)
[六角堂]
Excuse me.
不好意思
How do you feel?
感觉怎么样了
Much better.
好多了
Hattori.
服部
You sneaked into Sannou Temple eight years ago, didn't you?
八年前你偷偷溜进去的就是山能寺吧
How did you know that?
你怎么知道
Idiot.
白痴
I knew everything when I saw your expression when you were looking at the cherry blossoms.
当时看到你看樱花的表情就什么都知道了
There happened to be the lattice window you mentioned.
旁边还正好有你说的格子窗
Yeah.
是啊
I found this crystal bead just under the cherry blossom tree.
就在那棵樱花树下捡到了这颗水晶珠
I don't want to disappoint you.
虽然不想泼你冷水
But this crystal bead,
可是这颗水晶珠
I'm afraid it wasn't from your first crush.
恐怕不是你的初恋情人掉的哦
What are you saying?
你说什么
I'm afraid this is
恐怕这是山能寺被窃的佛像额上的白毫
Urna.
白毫
Is it the shiny thing in the middle of the Buddha's forehead?
就是镶在佛像额头正中那个发光的东西吗
Yep.
对
Buddha statues often use crystal beads to make urna.
佛像常常用水晶珠来做白毫
The masks in Noh plays are also like this.
能剧中的面具也是这样的
This is what I think.
我的推理是这样的
Eight years ago, the Genjibotaru gang
八年前源氏萤盗贼团
sneaked into the Sannou Temple,
潜入了山能寺的佛堂
and stole the hidden Buddha statue.
偷走了密藏着的佛像
But on the way out,
但是在搬运的途中
the urna fell off.
白毫脱落  掉在了地上
The leader, Yoshitsune, noticed this
随后注意到这点的首领义经
and sent a subordinate to find it at Sannou Temple.
派了一名手下一直找到了山能寺
Right then...
就在那时
I want red bean soup.
我想吃红豆汤
I want honey bean ice.
我想吃蜜豆冰
The helpless leader kept the Buddha statue in the warehouse that Mr. Sakura searched in.
无计可施的首领把佛像保管在樱先生搜寻的那个仓库里
But eight years later, the murderer found out by accident
然而八年后凶手偶然得知了
that you were the boy from eight years ago.
你就是八年前的那个少年
Because of the magazine?
是那本杂志吗
At the same time,
与此同时
there were also incidents inside the gang.
盗贼团伙的内部也发生了事件
I think the leader might have been seriously ill.
恐怕是首领得了重病
The leader knows that he's dying,
知道自己死期将近的首领
so he hid the Buddha statue he stole from Sannou Temple elsewhere.
把从山能寺偷来的佛像藏到其他地方
He then divided the hits of the location to his men in pieces.
然后把那幅暗示着佛像地点的画分给手下
He left his last words, stating that the one who solves the riddle will become the new leader.
留下解开谜题的人就是新首领的遗言
He then died.
然后就死了
The men desperately tried to solve the riddle, but failed.
手下们拼命的想解开谜题但没能成功
At that time,
那时
Mr. Sakura
成员之一的樱先生
actively reached out to the murderer for collaboration.
主动找到凶手合作
He used the murderer's swordsmanship to kill all the other accomplices,
利用凶手的剑术把其他的同伙都干掉
then the two of them would go look for the Buddha statue and urna,
然后两个人再把佛像和白毫的去向找出来
and then split money from selling it.
平分卖佛像得到的钱
Yes.
是啊
I'm afraid only Mr. Sakura, the only antique dealer in the gang,
恐怕盗贼团伙中只有作为古董商的樱先生
had the channels for selling the stolen goods.
掌握着贩卖赃物的渠道
That's why he firmly believed that he was absolutely safe.
所以才坚信自己是绝对安全的
The murderer pretended to listen to Mr. Sakura.
凶手假装听从了樱先生的主意
But he actually had planned to
其实他原本就打算
kill all the accomplices and to take the treasure for himself.
把所有同伙都杀掉然后独吞宝物
But to achieve this,
但是要达到这个目的
(Bukkoji Temple)in any case, he had to solve the riddle of the painting left by the leader.
无论如何得先解开首领留下的那幅画的谜题
So the murderer...
于是凶手
Thought of having the famous detective, Kogoro Mouri, to solve the riddle for him.
就想到让名侦探毛利小五郎来帮他解开这个谜题
Bukkoji Temple, we're here.
佛光寺  就是这里
But is the Buddha statue really hidden here?
但是佛像真的藏在这里面吗
I have a feeling that something's wrong.
总觉得有什么地方不对劲
What is it?
怎么了
Kudo, what have you got?
工藤  你想到什么了
This…
这是
Gyokuryuji Temple
玉龙寺
The point in the painting, could it refer to this?
画中的点指的就是这里啊
Toyama. It's me.
是和叶  是我
The girl's with me.
这个女孩在我手上
Come to the Gyokuryuji Temple on Mount Kurama alone an hour later.
一小时后一个人到鞍马山的玉龙寺来
If you dare call the police,
你敢报警的话
she'll be dead.
她就没命了
Heiji, don't come. You'll get yourself killed!
平次  不要来  你会被杀掉的
Toyama, Toyama!
和叶  和叶
Hattori.
服部
It's Toyama. She got kidnapped.
和叶  和叶她被抓走了
What?
什么
He asked me to get to Gyokuryuji Temple on Mount Kurama
他让我一个小时以后
an hour later by myself.
一个人到鞍马山的玉龙寺去
Gyokuryuji Temple.
玉龙寺
Good.
正好
Let's go together now.
我们两个现在就去
Hattori!
服部
(Modoribashi Bridge)
[归桥]
The dutiful son who learned of his father's death hurried back to Kyoto.
得知父亲死讯的孝子迅速赶回京都
It just so happened that the funeral procession passed this bridge.
恰好送葬队伍从这座桥上通过
At that moment, the father suddenly woke.
就在那时父亲突然苏醒
Legend has it, the father and the dutiful son got to speak in the end.
最后父亲和孝子得以交谈的传说
Hello.
喂
(Mount Kurama)
[鞍马山]
(Gyokuryuji Temple)
[玉龙寺]
The leader has instructed
首领的指示
that the knife will be placed in Benkei's drawer.
预备的刀放在弁庆的抽屉
The bows and arrows are in the Rokkaku drawer.
弓和箭放在六角的抽屉
Benkei's drawer is in...
弁庆的抽屉在...
Starting from the top, 1 2 3...
从上面开始1  2  3...
What are you talking about?
在说什么呢
Benkei and Rokkaku drawer.
弁庆和六角的抽屉
Bukkoji Temple?
佛光寺
I heard the two of them saying that.
我听他们两个这么说的
Seriously, where did those two go?
真是的  那两个家伙跑到哪里去了
Toyama didn't answer her phone either.
打和叶的手机也不接
Bukkoji Temple.
玉龙寺
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Really? We'll be home soon.
是吗  我们马上就到家了
Excuse me,
请问一下
where is this Gyokuryuji Temple?
这个玉龙寺  现在在哪里
In the deep mountains of Mount Kurama.
在鞍马山的深山里
But I heard that it was abandoned a long time ago.
不过听说很久前就已经是废寺了
Thanks.
谢谢
Kurama Mountain.
鞍马山
So slow.
真慢呀
Knowing that it is a trap, how can one be fooled so easily?
明知是陷阱哪有这么容易上当的
Really?
是吗
Probably just scared.
我看是害怕了吧
Heiji.
平次
You didn't hurt Toyama,
你这家伙
did you?
没有伤害和叶吧
I'm fine, Heiji.
我没事  平次
This is what you really wanted, right?
你真正想要的是这个吧
In order to retrieve this crystal bead,
为了取回这颗水晶珠
you attacked me here yesterday.
你昨天才会在这山里袭击我
But you failed.
虽然失败了
Then, to take this treasure for your own,
接着你为了独吞宝物
you killed Mr. Sakura at the teahouse in Ponto-cho.
在先斗町的茶屋把樱先生也杀害了
Why did you choose Ponto-cho instead of other places?
为什么特地选择在先斗町而不是别的地方
Because it was the only place with a river flowing behind the teahouse.
是因为只有那里的茶屋后面有河水流过
River?
河
After you killed Mr. Sakura who was looking for the Buddha statue in the warehouse,
你将在仓库找佛像的樱先生杀害死之后
you placed the company's anti-theft tracker used to find missing children
将保安公司的防窃或者用于寻找走失儿童的跟踪器
in an empty bottle with the weapon, and dumped them together.
和凶器一起放到空瓶中扔掉
Then you logged into the security company's webpage with your mobile phone,
之后用手机上网登陆保安公司的网页
found the location of the tracker and reclaimed it.
查到跟踪器的位置  然后回收
You then hid and waited for me,
之后你埋伏好等着我的出现
trying to kill me with the same short knife.
企图用同一把短刀来杀我
Although you failed because of Tomoya,
虽然这次凶杀因为和叶的阻扰而失败了
you deliberately left a short knife for disguise,
但你故意留下了短刀企图脱罪
so that people would think it was the murderer who fled the tea house with a weapon.
让人以为是凶手当时带着凶器逃离了茶屋
Right, Mr. Saijo?
是吧  西条大河先生
No, maybe I should call you Musashibo Benkei.
不  也许我该叫你武藏坊弁庆
Indeed the high school detective, Heiji Hattori, from Naniwa Castle.
真不愧是浪花之城的高中生侦探服部平次呀
How did you know that I am the murderer?
怎么知道我是凶手的
Because you pretended that you didn't know archery.
因为你刻意假装自己不会射箭
But when you sat,
你就坐的时候
you moved your right foot back half a step before sitting down.
把右脚向后挪了半步才坐下的
(Half-foot drag) That is called "half-foot drag".
那是被称作“拖半足”的
People who practice archery have the habit of sitting like that.
练射箭的人才有的就坐习惯
(The pronunciation of arrow pillow is the same as Yamakura) So when asked who knows archery,
而且被问及谁会射箭时
you accidentally said "yamakura".
箭枕(yamakura)音同山仓(yamakura)
It seems like Yamakura...
这样说的话好像山仓...
You didn't mean "Yamakura", the owner of the teahouse.
你当时并不是指茶屋的老板娘“山仓”
Instead,
而是想说搭弓箭的枕穴“箭枕”
(Yamakura)That is, the second joint of the thumb at left hand purlicue when shooting an arrow with a bow.
即搭弓射箭时左手虎口处的拇指第二关节
I think you wanted to say
我看你当时是想说
it seems like Suzu Chika's yamakura is injured.
这样说的话好像千贺铃的箭枕受伤了
However, only those who practice archery would know the word "yamakura".
然而只有练射箭的人知道“箭枕”这个词
Besides, Ryuen doesn't know archery,
加上龙圆又是个外行
and he even mispronounced bow and arrow.
连弓弦都读错了
Ryuen and I used to practice in the same kendo field.
我和龙圆他们原本是在一个剑道场上修行的
But one day,
不过我有一天
I learned that there is an ancient school of kendo called Yoshitsune in Kyoto.
得知了在京都有个叫义经流的古老剑术流派
So I started to study Chronicles of Yoshitsune by myself.
我于是开始独自学习义经流
I left the kendo field two years ago,
并且在两年前退出了剑道场
and became the heir of Chronicles of Yoshitsune.
当上了义经流的继承者
Benkei's Yoshitsune.
弁庆的义经流啊
I wanted to be Yoshitsune more than being Benkei.
比起弁庆来我更想要成为义经
Do you know how much I wanted to be Yoshitsune?
你知道我有多么想成为义经吗
But the position of Yoshitsune was occupied by the leader.
但是义经之位被首领占据
I myself, the noblest in the gang, became Benkei.
盗贼团里最高贵的我竟然成了弁庆
If you want to have the Buddha statue to yourself, sure enough, it's for the money.
你想独占佛像果然还是为了钱吧
Yes, but not for selfish desires.
没错  不过并不是为了私欲
I will use the money to build a dojo in Kyoto.
我要用那些钱在京都兴办义经流的道场
The Chief Priest has always been leading the temple here.
首领一直在这个寺院当住持
Even after the temple was abandoned, he has been in charge of it.
即使寺院荒废后也一直由他掌管
I asked him to let me be the dojo of Yoshitsune.
我要求他让给我作义经流的道场
But the leader passed away three months ago.
可是  三个月前首领去世
The temple will be demolished,
寺院将被拆除
and it can no longer be used as a dojo.
已经不能再作为道场使用了
I want to ask you something.
我想问你一件事
Were you just using Mr. Ryuen?
你只是在利用龙圆先生而已吧
Yes, I heard him mentioning the Buddha statue before,
没错  之前听他提到过佛像的事
so after I sent the letter to Sannou Temple,
我把那信送到山能寺后
he indeed came to discuss it with me.
他果然来找我商量
I recommended Kogoro Mouri to come here specifically.
我故意推荐了毛利小五郎来此
I killed Sakura because even without him,
杀了樱是因为我就算不靠他
I'll also be able to find buyers of the Buddha statue.
也能找到佛像的买主
Thanks to the convenient Internet.
多亏现在有这么方便的网络
So, let's stop here.
那么  话就讲到这里
Hurry up and hand over the crystal bead.
还不快把水晶珠交过来
I can give it to you, but you have to let Toyama go first.
给你可以  你先放了和叶
OK.
好呀
Only if you tell me where the Buddha statue is.
如果你告诉我佛像藏在哪里的话
What?
什么
Come on, where is the Buddha statue?
快说  佛像到底在哪里
In this temple.
就在这个寺院里
What?
什么
This is the so-called riding a donkey to find a donkey.
这就是所谓的骑驴找驴吧
That's nonsense!
你胡说
I searched through this temple a long time ago and it was nowhere to be found!
我早把这个寺院搜查过了  到处都没有
I'm not talking nonsense.
我没胡说
Toyama, run!
和叶  快跑
Heiji!
平次
They are my beloved apprentices.
他们是我的爱徒
Don't move.
你们不要出手
Heiji!
平次
Stop it. He is not Heiji!
住手  他不是平次
Who are you? Who?
谁  是谁  你是谁
Shinichi Kudo.
工藤新一
A detective.
侦探
What?
什么
What did you say?
你说什么
You let him take the medicine?
你让他吃了那个药吗
Kudo called and asked me
工藤来电话问我
if there was a way to temporarily change back to Shinichi Kudo.
有没有暂时变回工藤新一的方法
But the antidote test product of APTX4869 was gone.
不过APTX4869的解药试验品已经没有了
And Paikaru was taken as a cold medicine so
以前当作感冒药喝下去的白干
there are antibodies. It wouldn't work.
也已经产生了抗体不起作用了
So I suddenly had the idea
于是我突然想到
that to take the medicine that brings a severe cold first,
先吃那个会产生重感冒症状的药
and then to have Paikaru afterwards,
之后再喝白干
done only once,
只是一次的话
maybe it could help him change back to his body.
也许真的可以变回原来的身体
Then what?
然后呢
As I expected, the experiment was very successful.
如我所料  实验非常成功
Kudo changed back to himself.
工藤君变回了原样
But because it's a bad cold,
不过因为是和重感冒一样
he's very weak.
身体非常虚弱
We can't guarantee his safety.
不能保证生命安全呢
What about Heiji?
那么平次的状况呢
He has to rest before the comprehensive examination tomorrow.
明天做全面检查前必须静养
So Kudo asked me to take care of him.
所以工藤拜托我好好看着他
Kudo.
工藤
Damn, how dare you lie to me!
可恶  竟敢骗我
I have to let Toyama get out of here first.
无论如何得先让和叶逃离这儿
But my body is not responding.
可身体却不听使唤了
Darn, the Paikaru is losing its effect.
糟糕  白干快要失效了
Although you are invincible as a detective,
虽然当侦探你天下无敌
as a samurai, you're pretty bad.
但是当武士却差得很了
Hattori.
服部
Heiji.
平次
Sorry for the wait, Toyama.
让你久等了  和叶
What do you think? Idiot!
你还好意思说  大笨蛋
What did you do?
你都干什么去了
Kudo.
工藤
You stole my clothes,
你居然偷我的衣服
and
而且
I don't know what you put on your face
我虽然不知道你在脸上涂了什么
but I'm not that dark.
我可没有那么黑哟
Really?
是吗
Forget it, leave it to me, go now!
算了  这儿交给我  你快走
Hide before you change.
在变小之前先躲起来
Wait until your body recovers and come back.
等身体复原了再回来
Stop. I'm your opponent.
站住  你们的对手是我
Toyama,
和叶
don't tell anyone about Kudo,
见到工藤的事不要告诉任何人
including Ran.
包括小兰
Not even Ran? Why?
连小兰都不能说吗  为什么
No reason.
不为什么
It's better not to know if she can't see him.
反正见不到  还不如不知道的好
The two of you won't leave here alive.
你们两个别想活着回去
This knife is really bad.
这刀还真是够破
Hurry up!
快追
Did you find him?
找到了吗
Not yet.
还没有
Look harder!
再好好找
What happened...
发生什么...
Hush, be quiet. Don't make a sound.
嘘  安静  别出声
Shinichi.
新一
Your expression is still the same as then.
你的表情还是和那时侯一样呢
Why are you sweating so much?
怎么搞的  大汗淋漓呢
And what happened to those people just now?
而且刚才那些人是怎么回事
Where did they hide?
躲哪儿去了
It doesn't matter now. Let's go back first.
不管了  先回去
Sorry Ran.
对不起  兰
I can't meet you yet...
现在我还不能和你见面...
It's locked from the inside. The door won't open.
从里面锁上了  门打不开
Think of a way!
快想办法
The smell of this tatami…
这个榻榻米的味道
This is the room that I got locked in.
正是我被囚禁的房间呀
Go get the axe, hurry up.
去拿斧头来  快
Damn, it's only a matter of time before the door is knocked open.
可恶  门被撞开也只是时间问题了
Is there anything to be used as a weapon?
就没有什么能当武器的东西吗
Why is there a big cabinet with so many drawers?
怎么有个这么多抽屉的大柜子啊
The knife is in Benkei's drawer.
预备的刀在弁庆的抽屉
Bows and arrows are in the Rokkaku drawer.
弓和箭放在六角的抽屉
Heiji, there is a knife in Benkei's drawer.
平次  在弁庆的抽屉里有刀
What? In this drawer?
什么  这个柜子里边吗
But there are so many drawers.
可是
How do I know which one belongs to Benkei?
这么多抽屉我怎么知道哪个是弁庆的
I seem to have seen this before.
这个好像在哪见过
Isn't the line on the drawer the same as the streets of Kyoto?
抽屉上的线条和京都的街不是一样的吗
Got it. This line is Karasuma Street.
知道了  这线是鸟丸街
This line here is Takoyakushido Street.
这线是蛸药师街
Wait.
等一下
Is it possible that the drawer is named after places?
难不成是按地名来命名抽屉的
Places?
地名
Yes, Rokkaku is Rokkaku-do.
是呀  六角就是六角堂
Benkei's drawer is...
弁庆的抽屉就是...
The location of Benkei Stone.
弁庆石的所在地
From the third Fuyacho Street...
从三条的麸屋町街...
Right, Temari.
对  手球歌
Maru-take
丸竹  夷
Maru-take...
丸竹  夷...
What's next?
之后是什么来着
Damn it. I can't remember.
可恶  想不起来了
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹  夷二　押御池
Yome-san-Rokkaku-Tako-Nishiki
新娘　六角　蛸锦
Heiji, the third line is the second street above Nishiki.
平次  三条在章鱼(蛸)上面的第二条街
The second street above Nishiki.
章鱼上面的第二条街
East-west road.
东西向的道路
Temple Miyuki Fuyacho Tomi.
寺  御幸  麸屋  富
Fuyacho is the third.
麸屋町在第三个
It's here.
在这里
Go to hell.
去死吧
Unity in and out, with a unique knife pattern.
表里合一  拥有独特的刀纹
this knife is Muramasa, right?
这刀是妖刀村正吧
Used to deal with the demon possessed by Yoshitsune,
用于对付被义经附身的魔头
it could not be better.
再好不过了
What?
什么
Get out of the way!
闪开
What are you guys doing?
你们在干什么
Go after him!
还不快给我追
Yes!
是
Listen well.
听好
I'll distract them, and you have to run.
我吸引他们的注意力  你趁机快逃
No, I want to be with you.
不要  我要和你一起
Do as I say.
照我说的去做
Heiji.
平次
There they are!
在那里
Run!
快走
You guys go and catch that little girl.
你们去抓那个小姑娘
Yes.
是
Conan.
柯南
Toyama, where's Heiji?
和叶姐姐  平次哥哥呢
There.
在那
Hattori!
服部
Damn it.
可恶
I want to call the police, but I have no signal.
想要报警  但手机又没信号
That's it!
用这个
Extinguish the fire!
快  快灭火
Ok, as long as someone can spot this fire.
好  只要有人能发现这火
Hey, Ran.
喂  小兰
Are you okay?
醒过来了吗
Dad.
爸爸
Where's Shinichi?
新一呢
Are you confused?
你睡晕了吧
Why would he be here?
那家伙怎么可能在这里
Speaking of that, why did you fall asleep here?
说起来你怎么会睡在这儿
Dad, why did you come here?
爸爸  倒是你为什么会来这里
I told him to.
我告诉他的
Toyama got kidnapped by the Genjibotaru gang.
和叶被源氏萤团伙绑架了
Mr. Mouri!
毛利先生
It's time for us to battle for victory.
我们也该决一胜负了吧
Can't wait.
求之不得
I won't be fooled anymore.
我可不会再上当了
Then, how about this?
那么  这个如何呢
A dagger?
短剑吗
This is no ordinary dagger.
这可不是一般的短剑
The blade is smeared with a poison that kills instantly.
刃上涂了见血封喉的剧毒哦
What?
什么
You'll die with a tiny cut.
被擦破点皮你就成佛了
What a despicable guy.
好卑鄙的家伙
It's not good. Heiji is in danger.
不好  平次危险
There is nowhere to run to now.
现在无处可逃了吧
There are bows and arrows waiting.
下面还有弓箭伺候呢
We've got to find a way to save him.
得想办法救他
Conan.
柯南
Wait.
等等
Hey, this way!
喂  这边
Watch this!
看我的
Go, Hattori!
上啊  服部
Heiji.
平次
The Benkei who wants to be Yoshitsune, right?
想成为义经的弁庆是吗
If you were Benkei,
若你是弁庆
Yoshitsune would have been killed at the Ataka.
义经早在当年那个安宅关口毙命了
The master got defeated.
师父被打败了
Grab them all!
全部都抓起来
This is it, Conan.
这下好了  柯南
Did you call Heiji "Hattori" just now?
不过  刚才你是不是叫平次“服部”来着
I'm sorry, it just came out.
对不起  一时脱口而出
Heiji.
平次
This temple.
这个寺院
Now all mysteries have been solved.
这下  迷团全部解开了
It seems that the effect of the medicine is only temporary.
看来药效也还是暂时性的而已
But thanks to you, I have collected a lot of important data.
不过多亏你又让我收集到了不少重要的数据哦
Are you okay? Heiji.
没事吧  平次
I'm okay.
还好啦
But where is the Buddha statue?
不过佛像到底在哪儿
Hattori, have you seen Shi...
服部  你见过新...
What?
什么
Nothing.
没什么
Sure enough, it was just a dream.
果然只是场梦呀
(Sannou Temple  Morning)
[山能寺(早晨)]
I'm so sorry.
实在是无地自容
In the end, I couldn't find the Buddha statue for you.
最后也没能帮您找回佛像
It's okay.
没关系没关系
Don't mention it. It's the Buddha's decision.
哪里哪里  这也是佛祖他自己的决定
Don't worry about it.
不用那么在意了
Everyone, take care.
各位  一路保重
Goodbye.
再见
But it's really difficult now.
不过这下还真是难办了
We only got one hour before the consecration ceremony.
距离开光仪式  只有1小时了
What's so rough?
有什么为难的
If you have it, you can show it. If not, then leave it.
有则示有  无便示无  有无皆空
Bhaisajyaguru is back.
药师如来  回来了
(Gyokuryuji Temple  Early morning)
[玉龙寺(凌晨)]
I found it, Kudo.
找到了  工藤
Like I said.
和我说的一样吧
Unexpectedly, the shape of the temple was arranged in the word "Jade".
没想到寺院的形状竟然会排列成“玉”字
And the dot sits right at the clock tower.
而点的位置正好是这座钟楼
I didn't even notice it.
连我也没注意到呀
Add a cover to "Jade", it becomes “Treasure”.
给“玉”加上个宝盖  不就是“宝”字了么
And treasure cover refers to the roof.
而宝盖就是指的屋顶
I see.
原来如此呀
It's as good as ever.
这下就完好如初了
Yes.
是呀
Those two guys are really the best of partners.
那两个家伙  真是最佳拍档呀
Just like Yoshitsune and Benkei.
简直像义经和弁庆一样
Detective Hattori and Mouri?
服部少年和毛利名侦探吗
It seems that you still need practice.
看来你的修行还是不够呢
What?
怎么回事
So next up, Ayumi.
那么  接下来是步美  请
Okay.
好
It's so cute.
真可爱呢
I really want to take you home.
好想把你带回家
Not this. It's my best friend.
这可不行  它是我最好的朋友
Inspector, you don't have a lot of human friends?
警部先生难道你的人类朋友很少吗
I mistook you two as murderers, so sorry.
之前把你们两个误想成了凶手  实在抱歉
No problem.
没关系了
Actually, I knew who my father was。
其实是我知道了自己的父亲是谁
And I told him that he didn't have to send me money anymore.
让他不用再继续寄钱给我了
Who is
你的父亲
your father?
是谁
That's a secret.
这是秘密
That old bald donkey.
那个老秃驴
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹　夷二　押御池
Yome-san-Rokkaku-Tako-Nishiki…
新娘　六角　蛸...
Not a "yome" but an "ane", fool.
不是“新娘”  是“姐姐”  笨蛋
Where did you learn this song?
你在哪里学的这首歌
From relatives in Kyoto,
在京都的亲戚家
when I was in the third grade of elementary school.
大概小学三年级的时候吧
I learned it when I went with you.
和你一起去玩的时候学到的
With me?
和我一起
You don't remember?
不记得吗
I wasn't even ready but you couldn't wait,
对了  我当时还没准备好你就等不及了
and said you wanted to go and play at Sannou Temple. So you ran out.
说要去山能寺玩  就先跑出去了
My relatives dressed me in a kimono,
当时亲戚帮我换上和服
and I put my hair in a bun with some makeup.
还盘了发髻  化了些妆
Then I went to Sannou Temple to look for you.
然后我到山能寺找你
But I couldn't find you.
结果到处都没找到
So I played with the ball for a while and went back.
于是拍了一会儿球就回去了
Seriously though,
真是
I wanted to let you see
还想让你看看
that cherry blossom tree. It was so beautiful with the cherry blossoms falling down.
那棵樱花树下落樱缤纷  真是美极了
Maru-Take-Ebisu-Ni-Oshi-Oike
丸竹　夷二　押御池
Yome-san-Rokkaku-Tako-Nishiki…
新娘　六角　蛸锦
Finally,
终于见到了
we meet again.
见到了
Did you see your first love? Heiji.
见到初恋情人了吗  平次
Who is it? That geisha?
是谁呢  那个舞妓吗
I won't tell you, ever, idiot.
一辈子都不会告诉你的  笨蛋
You petty kid, tell me!
有什么嘛  小气鬼  告诉人家嘛
Or maybe I will tell you in 1500 years.
也可以  再过1500年也许会告诉你
What?
什么嘛
Conan, what are you doing?
柯南  你在干什么啊
Why are you sweating so much?
怎么搞的  大汗淋漓呢
Shinichi.
新  新一
Speaking of that, I called Shinichi
说起来我给新一哥哥打了电话
and asked him to act as Heiji to save Toyama,
让他扮成平次哥的模样去救和叶姐
right?
是吧
Yeah, but that guy is really weak.
是啊  不过那家伙实在是弱不禁风
He ran away midway.
中途跑掉了
Told me not to tell and he said it first.
明明自己说的不要告诉别人
That's right.
是这样呢
So it was Shinichi after all.
果然  果然那是新一呢
I finally saw you.
终于见到你了
I want an ice cream.
要一个冰淇淋
OK.
好的
300 yen.
300日圆
I'm the only one who didn't see the person I wanted to meet in the end.
最终没见到想见的人的就我一个
Suzuki will definitely see Kyogoku-kun soon.
园子也一定会很快见到京极君的
Most definitely.
一定会的
But I have no patience to wait for people.
但是  我最没耐心等人的
Isn't Ran the same?
小兰不也是这样的么
I don't hate waiting for someone.
我可并不讨厌等人呢
Because the longer you wait,
因为等得越久
when we meet again...
重逢时就...
Your expression is still the same as then.
你的表情还是和那时侯一样呢
the happier we will be.
越幸福呢
Darn,
可恶　刚才这句酸酸的台词
I really want Kudo to hear this cheesy line.
真想让工藤听到